In the last segment we defined
authenticated encryption, but I didn't
在上一节我们定义了认证加密 但是我并没有
really show you why authenticated
encryption is the right notion of
向你们展示为什么认证加密是一种安全概念
security. In this segment I want to show
you that authenticated encryption in fact
在这一节中 我想向你们展示 认证加密事实上
is a very natural notion of security and
I'll do it by showing you that it defends
是一种很自然的安全概念 我将通过展示它如何抵抗
against a very powerful attack called a
chosen cipher text attack. So in fact we
强大的选择密文攻击来说明这一点 事实上我们
already saw a number of examples of a
chosen cipher text attack so imagine the
已经看到一些选择密文攻击的例子了 想象
adversary has some cipher text C that
it wants to decrypt. And what it can do
敌手想破解某些密文C 他能做到的是
is, for example, fool the decryption
server into decrypting some cipher text
比如 欺骗解密服务器来破解某些
but not actually the cipher text c. So we
already saw some examples of that. If you
不是密文c的密文 我们已经看到过一些这样的例子
remember in the first segment, we looked
at an adversary that can submit arbitrary
如果你还记得 在第一节中 我们看到过能够提交任意
cipher text, and if the plaintext happened
to start with destination equals 25, then
密文的敌手  而且如果明文正好以目的端口25开头 那么
the adversary is actually given the
plaintext in the clear. So that's an
敌手事实上就能清楚地获得这一明文
example of an adversary that can obtain
the decryption of certain cipher texts but
这就是一个敌手可以获得特定密文解密结果的例子
not all cipher texts. Another example we
saw is an adversary that can learn
但他不能获得全部密文 我们看到的另一个例子是 敌手能够
something about the plaintext by
submitting cipher texts to the decrypter.
通过向解密者提交密文来获得有关明文的信息
So we have this example where the
adversary submits encrypted TCP/IP packets
所以我们有这样的例子 敌手提交加密的TCP/IP数据包
to the decryption server, and if the
decryption server sends back an ACK, the
给解密服务器 如果解密服务器发回了一个ACK
adversary learns that the decrypted plain
text had a valid check sum. And otherwise,
敌手就会知道这个解密明文的校验和有效 否则
the decrypted plain text didn't have a
valid check sum. So this is, again, an
解密明文的校验和无效 这又是一个
example of a chosen cipher text attack,
where the attacker submits cipher text,
选择密文攻击的例子 在这个例子中 攻击者提交密文
and learns something about the decryption
of that cipher text. So to address this
然后就能获得那个密文解密后的相关信息 为了解决
type of threats, we're gonna define a very
general notion of security, called chosen
这种威胁 我们将要定义一个非常广义的安全上的概念 叫做选择密文安全
cipher text security. So here, we're gonna
give the adversary a lot of power, okay?
在这我们让攻击者有强大的能力
So he can do both chosen plain text
attack, and a chosen cipher text attack.
他既可以进行选择明文攻击也可以进行选择密文攻击
In other words, he can obtain the
encryption of arbitrary messages of his
换句话说 他可以获得他选择的任何信息的加密结果
choice. And he can decrypt any cipher text
of his choice, other than some challenge
他也可以解密任何他选择的密文 而不是挑战密文
cipher texts. And as I showed you before,
this is actually a fairly conservative
正如我之前向你们展示的一样 这其实是一个很保守的
modeling of real life. In real life,
often, the attacker can fool the, the
现实情况的模型 在真实世界中 经常地 攻击者可以欺骗
decrypter, into decrypting certain cipher
texts for the attacker, but not all cipher
解密者 使其为攻击者解密特定密文 但不能解密全部密文
texts. So the model here is that the
attacker has a certain cipher text that it
所以在这种情况下 攻击者有其想解密的特定密文
wants to decrypt. It can interact with
the decrypter by issuing these chosen
他可以通过将所选密文的询问发送给解密者的方式
cipher text queries to the decrypter.
Namely, to decrypt various cipher text
与解密者互动  也就是说 解密各种密文
other than the challenge cipher text. And
then the adversary's goal is to break
而不是挑战密文 然后攻击者的目标就是破坏
semantic security of the challenge cipher
text. So you notice that we're giving the
挑战密文的语义安全 你会注意到我们赋予敌手
adversary a lot of power. And all we're
asking you to do is break semantic
强大的能力 现在我们让你做的就是破坏语义安全
security. So it's going to be fairly
difficult to design systems that are
所以设计能够对抗这种攻击者的系统
secure against such adversaries.
Nevertheless, we're going to do it. So
将会变得非常困难 虽然如此 我们还是要设计出它来
let's define the chosen cipher text
security model more precisely. So, as
让我们更精确的定义下选择密文安全模型
usual, we have a cipher (E, D). And we're
gonna define two experiments, experiment
通常 我们有密码(E, D)  然后我们将要定义两个实验
zero and experiment one. So this should
look somewhat familiar by now. The
实验0和实验1 现在大家对这个应该挺熟悉了
challenger is gonna start off by choosing
a random key. And now the adversary is
挑战者开始时选择一个随机密钥 现在敌手将
gonna submit queries to this challenger.
Every query can be one of two types. It
提交询问给挑战者 每个询问可以是两种类型之一
can be a chosen plain text query, or it
can be a chosen cipher text query. So a
选择明文询问 或者选择密文询问
chosen plain text query, as we already
know. Basically, the adversary submits two
我们知道 在一个选择明文询问中 敌手提交两个消息
messages, M zero and M1. They have to be
the same length. And the adversary
M0和M1 它们必须长度一样
receives the encryption of either M zero
if we're in experiment zero, or M1, if we're
如果是在实验0中 敌手会收到M0的加密 如果是在实验1中
in experiment one. So he receives the
encryption of the left or the right
则会收到M1 所以他收到的是左边或者右边
depending on whether we were in experiment
zero or in experiment one. The second type
取决于我们是在实验0中还是实验1中 第二种类型
of query is the more interesting one. This
is where the adversary submits an arbitrary
的询问更有趣 敌手提交他选择的任意密文
cipher text of his choice and what he gets
back is the decryption of that cipher
然后得到那个密文的解密
text. So you notice the adverary's allowed
to decrypt arbitrary cipher texts of his
你会注意到敌手被允许解密他选择的任意密文
choice. The only restriction is that the
cipher text is not one of the cipher texts
唯一的限制是 他所选的密文不是
that were obtained as a result of a CPA
query. And of course this wouldn't be fair
在CPA攻击的询问中获得的密文之一 当然这在其他情况下不合理
otherwise, because the attacker can simply
take one cipher text that was obtained
另外 因为攻击者可以轻松获得
from a CPA query. That's gonna to be
either the encryption of M0 or the
通过CPA询问得到的密文 那会是M0或者M1的加密结果
encryption of M1. If he could submit a CCA
query for that particular cipher text, he
如果他对那个特定的密文提交CCA询问
will in response either obtain M0 or M1,
and then he'll know whether he is in experiment
他将会获得M0或者M1作为回复 然后他就会知道他是在实验0
zero or experiment one. So this wouldn't
be fair. So we say that the CPA cipher
还是实验1中了 这不合理 所以我们说他收到的
texts that he received are the challenge
cipher texts. And he's allowed to decrypt
CPA密文是挑战密文 而且他被允许解密
any cipher texts of his choice, other than
these challenge cipher texts. And as
他所选的任何密文 除了这些挑战密文
usual, his goal is to determine whether
he's in experiment zero, or in experiment
通常 他的目标是确定他是在实验0还是实验1中
one. So I'm gonna emphasize again, that
this is an extremely powerful adversary.
所以我再强调一遍 这是个极其强大的敌手
One that can decrypt any cipher text of
his choice, other than the challenge
他能解密任何密文 除了挑战密文
cipher text. And still, he can't
distinguish whether he is in experiment
但是依然不能分清他是处在实验0中
zero, or in experiment one. So, as usual,
we say that the cipher is CCA secure,
还是实验1中 所以通常我们说一个密码CCA安全
chosen cipher text secure, if the
adversary behaves the same in experiment
也就是选择密文安全 是指敌手在实验0和
zero as it does in experiment one. Namely, it
cannot distinguish the two experiments. So
实验1中行为一致 也就是说他无法区分这两个实验
let's start with a simple example, and
show that, in fact, CBC with a random IV,
让我们以一个简单的例子开始 证明事实上带随机IV的CBC
is not CCA secure, is not secure against
chosen cipher text attacks. So let's see
不是CCA安全的 不是对选择密文攻击安全的 让我们看看
why that's the case. So what the
adversary's gonna start by doing, he's
为什么是这种情况 敌手刚开始要做的是
gonna simply submit two distinct messages,
M0 and M1. And let's just pretend that
提交两个不同的消息M0和M1 让我们假定
these messages are one block messages. And
what he's gonna get back is the CBC
这两个消息都是单个分组的 然后他会得到
encryption of either M0 or
M1. You notice the cipher text only has
M0或者M1的CBC加密结果 你会注意密文仅有一个分组
one block, because the plain texts were
only one block long. Now what is the
因为明文仅有一个分组的长度 现在
attacker gonna do? Well, he's gonna modify
this cipher text C that he was given into
攻击者将要做什么？他会修改他得到的密文C
C prime simply by changing the IV. Okay?
So he just takes the IV and XORs it with
为C'仅通过变化IV域 他将IV与1异或
one. That's it. This gives a new cipher
text, C prime, which is different from C
就是这样 这就得到了一个与C不同的新密文C'
and as a result it's perfectly valid for
the adversary to submit C prime as its
因此攻击者完全可以提交C'作为他的
chosen cipher text query. So he
asks the challenger please decrypt this C
选择密文询问 所以他请求挑战者为他解密这个C'
prime for me. The challenger, because c
prime is not equal to c, must decrypt c
因为C'不等于C 所以挑战者必须解密C'
prime. And now let's see, what happens
when he decrypts c prime? Well, what's the
现在让我们看看 当他解密C'的时候发生了什么？
decryption of c prime, let me ask you. So
you probably remember from the first
让我来问你 C’的解密结果是什么 你可能记得在第一部分中
segment that if we xor the IV by one, that
simply xors the plaintext by one. So now
如果我们将IV与1异或 这只是简单地将明文与1异或
that adversary received M0 xor one, or M1
xor one, and now he can perfectly tell
既然敌手收到了M0与1的异或 或是M1与1的异或 他完全可以知道
whether he's in experiment zero and, or in
experiment one. So the advantage of this
自己是在实验0还是实验1中 所以这个敌手的的胜率
adversary is basically one, because he can
very easily tell which experiment he's in.
基本上是1了 因为他可以很简单地知道他在哪个实验中
And as a result he can win the chosen
cipher text security game. So if you think
而作为结果他可以赢得这个选择密文安全游戏 所以如果你
about it for a second, you'll see that
this attack game exactly captured the first
稍微考虑一下 你会发现这种攻击游戏完全抓住了
active attack that we saw, where the
adversary slightly changed the cipher text
我们看到的第一个主动攻击的主要内容 在那里对手稍微改变了
that he was given. And then he got the
decrypter to decrypt it for him. And
他所得到的密文 然后他得以让解密者为他解密
therefore, he was able to eavesdrop on
messages that were not intended for the
因而 他能够窃听那些原本不向他公开的消息
adversary. So I wanna emphasize again that
this chosen cipher text game really does
所以我想再次强调 这个选择密文游戏真的
come up in real life, where the adversary
can submit cipher texts to the decrypter
会在现实中发生 敌手可以向解密者提交密文
and the decrypter can reveal information
about the plain text, or it can give the
然后解码者会披露有关明文的信息 或者他可以
plain text outright to the adversary for
certain cipher texts but not others. So
将那段密文的明文彻底地泄露给敌手 所以
this is a very natural notion of security,
and the question is, how do we design
这是一个非常基本的安全概念 然而问题是 我们如何设计
crypto-systems that are CCA secure? So I
claim that this authenticated encryption
一个CCA安全的密码体系？ 所以我认为这个我们之前定义的
notion that we defined before actually
implies chosen cipher text security, and
认证加密的概念实际上意味着选择密文安全性
this is why authenticated encryption is
such a natural concept. Okay? So the
这就是为什么认证加密是一种基本概念
theorem basically says, well, if you give
me a cipher that provides authenticated
这个理论基本上说的是 如果你给我提供了经过认证加密的密码
encryption, the cipher can withstand
chosen cipher text attacks. And more
这个密码就可以抵御选择密文攻击
precisely, the theorem says the following.
If we have an adversary that issues Q
更精确地说 这个理论的内容是 如果我们有个敌手正在做Q个询问
queries, in other words, at most, q CPA
queries and q chosen cipher text queries,
换句话说 最多的情况下 q个CPA询问和q个选择密文询问
then there are two efficient adversaries,
B1 and B2, that satisfy this inequality
这里有两个有实力的敌手 B1和B2 他们满足这个不等式
here. So since the scheme has
authenticated encryption, we know that
所以由于该组合存在认证加密 我们知道
this quantity is negligible because it's
CPA secure. And we know that this
这个量可以忽略不计 因为它是CPA安全的 然后我们也能知道
quantity is negligible because the
encryption scheme has cipher text
这个量可以忽略不计 因为加密方案具有密文
integrity. And as a result, since both
terms are negligible we know that
完整性 作为结果来说 由于二者皆可以忽略 我们可以得知
adversary's advantage in winning the CCA
game is also negligible. So let's prove
敌手在这个CCA游戏中的胜率也可以忽略不计了 我们来证明
this theorem. It's actually a very simple
theorem to prove. And so let's just do it
这个定理 这事实上是个很容易证明的定理 所以我们可以仅仅
as proof by pictures. Okay, so here we
have two copies of the CCA game, so this
通过画图来证明 我们这里有两个这个CCA游戏的副本
would be experiment zero. And the bottom
one is experiment one. You can see the
这就是实验0 然后底下这个是实验1 你可以看到
adversary's issuing CPA queries, and he's
issuing CCA queries, and at the end he
敌手正在进行CPA询问 还有CCA询问 然后在最后他
outputs, you know, a certain guess b,
let's call it b prime, and our goal is to
输出了一个确认的猜想b 这里我们叫它b' 我们的目标是
show that this b prime is
indistinguishable in both cases. In other
证明这个b'在两种情况下是不能被区分的 换句话说
words, probability that b prime is equal
to one in the top game is the same as the
b'在上面的游戏中等于1的概率和
probability that b prime is equal to one
in the bottom game. Okay, so the way we're
b'在底下的游戏中等于1的概率相等 所以我们
gonna do it is the following. Well, first
of all, we're gonna change the challenger
接下来这样做 首先 我们将对挑战者
a little bit, so that instead of actually
outputting the decryption of CCA queries,
做一些改变 使得 挑战者将总是输出底下的部分
the challenger is just gonna always output
bottom. So every time the adversary
而不是输出被解密的CCA询问 所以每次敌手
submits a CCA query, the challenger says
bottom. And I claim that these two
提交一个CCA询问 敌手回复底部 而且我认为这两个
games are, in fact, indistinguishable. In
other words, the adversary can't
游戏 事实上 是不可区分的 换句话说 敌手不能
distinguish these two games, for the
simple reason that, because the scheme has
区分出这两个游戏 原因很简单 因为这个组合存在
cipher text integrity, the adversary
simply cannot create a cipher text that's
密文完整性 敌手就是不能写出一份不包含在
not in C1 to CI-1 that decrypts to
anything other than bottom. That is the
C1到CI-1的密文 其解密后不是底下的内容 这就是
definition of cipher text integrity. And
as a result, again, because of cipher text
密文完整性的定义 结果又因为密文
integrity, it must be the case that every
chosen cipher text query that the
完整性 敌手进行的每个选择密文询问必然
adversary issues results in bottom. If the
adversary, in fact, could distinguish
只能获得底部的信息 如果敌手 事实上 可以区分
between the left game and the right game,
that would mean that at some point he
左边的游戏和右边的游戏 这意味着在某一时刻他
issued a query that decrypted to something
other than bottom. And that we could use
发出的询问解密出了不是底部的信息 然后我们可以用
to then break cipher text integrity of the
scheme. And since the scheme has
它来破坏这个组合的密文完整性 而且因为这个组合具有
cipher-text integrity, these left and
right games are indistinguishable. Okay,
密文完整性 这左边和右边的游戏就是不可区分的
so that's kind of a cute argument that
shows that it's very easy to respond to
这是种很聪明的论证 它证明如果你具有密文完整性
chosen cipher-text queries when you have
cipher-text integrity. And the same thing
你可以很容易地回复选择密文询问 然后同样的事情
exactly applies on the bottom, where we
can simply replace the chosen cipher-text
也适用于底部 在这里我们可以简单地将选择密文
responses by just always saying bottom.
Okay, very good. But now, since the chosen
回复替换成⊥ 好的 但是现在 因为选择
cipher text queries always respond in the
same way, they're not giving the adversary
密文询问总是回复相同的结果 它们不会给敌手提供
any information. The adversary always
knows that we're always gonna just respond
任何信息 敌手也知道我们总是回复⊥
with bottom. So we might as well just
remove these queries, 'cause they don't
所以我们同样可以简单地移除这些询问 因为它们
contribute any information to the
adversary. But now, once we remove these
并不给敌手提供任何信息 但是现在 一旦我们移除了这些
queries, the resulting game should look
fairly familiar. The top right game, and
询问 由此产生的游戏我们应该相当熟悉 右上角的游戏 和
the [bottom right] game are basically the two
games that come up in the definition of
（右下角）的游戏基本上就是两个我们在CPA安全定义中提出的游戏
CPA security. And as a result, because the
scheme is CPA secure, we know that the
结果 因为这个组合是CPA安全的 我们可以知道
adversary can't distinguish the top from
the bottom. And so now, by this change of
敌手不能对上面和下面进行区分 然后 通过这种对回应的改变
reasoning, we've proven that all of these
games are equivalent. And in particular,
我们已经证明了所有这些游戏都是相同的 特别是
the original two games that we started
with are also equivalent, and therefore,
最初我们提及的两个游戏也是相同的 因此
the adversary can't distinguish the top
left from the bottom left. And therefore,
敌手不能对左上和左下进行区分 因为
the scheme is CCA secure. So this gives
you the intuition as to why authenticated
这个组合是CCA安全的 所以这就使你对为什么认证
encryption is such a cool concept. Because
primarily it implies security against
加密是一种很棒的想法有了直观认识 因为基本上它意味着
chosen cipher test attacks. Okay, so as we
said authenticated encryption
对选择密文攻击的安全 所以就像我们所说的认证加密
ensures confidentiality. Even if the
adversary can decrypt a subset of the
确保了机密性 即使敌手可以破译密文的子集
cipher text, and more generally, even if
he can mount a general chosen cipher text attack,
或者更广泛地讲 即使他可以他可以实施一般选择密文攻击
he still is not going to be able to break
semantic security of the system. However,
他仍旧不能破坏系统的语义安全 然而
it is important to remember the two
limitations. First of all, it does not
记住两点局限性是很重要的 首先 它不能
prevent replay attacks on its own. We're
going to have to do something in addition
自己阻挡重放攻击 我们需要去做一些额外的事
to defend against replay attacks. We're
going to see several examples where if the
去抵御重放攻击 我们将会看到很多例子 如果
decryption engine reveals more information
about why a cipher text is rejected, it
解密系统透露了更多关于密文被拒绝的原因 它
doesn't just output bottom, but it
actually outputs more information, say, by
不仅仅只输出底层 但是它确实输出更多的信息 例如
timing attacks. And that explains why the
cipher text is rejected. Then in fact that
在时序攻击中 这解释了为什么密文被拒绝了 此外事实上它
can completely destroy security of the
authenticated encryption system. So we'll
可以完全摧毁认证加密系统的安全性 所以
see some cute attacks like this in a later
segment. Okay. So, in the next segment
我们将在后面的部分看到一些像这样聪明的攻击 在下一部分
we're gonna turn to constructing
authenticated encryption systems.
我们将会转而讨论如何构造认证加密系统